computerjobs.com 2000-12-07

# ComputerJobs.com Privacy Statement

|   
|  |  |   
---|---|---  
**Thursday**  
December 7, 2000  
**Question of the Day**  
What do you think is the primary cause of burnout?  
Low pay  
Long hours / No time off  
Dead-end job  
Too much pressure to meet schedules  
Management  
Poor working environment  

**[**Enter your Salary Information**](http://www.computerjobs.com/salary_survey.cfm) and you could win a free monitor! Are you making what you're worth? Take a look at our [1999 Survey Results](http://www.computerjobs.com/salary99/) and find out!**  

#1 in Customer Satisfaction  
  
Best In ClassBest Overall  
|  |  |    
| 

**PRIVACY STATEMENT**

This confirms that ComputerJobs.com is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. The privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for www.ComputerJobs.com.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact our site coordinator by email at [privacy@ComputerJobs.com](mailto:privacy@computerjobs.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe [http://www.truste.org.users/watchdog.html](http://www.truste.org/users/watchdog.html). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns.

   **OUR COMMITMENT TO YOU**

The ComputerJobs.com community consists of high tech professionals who understand the importance of privacy when searching for job opportunities. We have safeguards in place to protect the privacy and confidentiality of IT professionals and employers. ComputerJobs.com joins other Internet industry leaders in encouraging the responsible use and dissemination of information over the Web.

   **INFORMATION COLLECTION**

For all processes that require information collection, ComputerJobs.com is committed to providing the highest level of security and privacy for IT professionals and employers. ComputerJobs.com is the sole collector of information from IT professionals. That information is used only for the purpose of matching skills, expertise, and interest with potential job opportunities. It is never released to third parties of any kind. 

We use various methods to collect information on our site such as registration forms, contests, surveys, request forms, contact-us, and mail-to's. The information collected is used to provide timely feedback and quality site content and is never given or sold to third parties. 

ComputerJobs.com collects system-related information such as IP address, browser type, and operating system type and uses it for system administration purposes. This information helps diagnose problems with our servers, monitor traffic patterns, and site usage. System information also assists us in identifying the most popular areas of our site, so we can continue to deliver content that is most important and relevant to our users. We use email addresses on occasion to send out notifications whenever there are changes and/or enhancements that will affect a user's interaction with our site. 

       **Information Collected from IT Professionals:**

> *  **Resume Registration**  
>  To place a resume online, IT professionals must complete our resume registration. The resume registration process requests the following information: 
> 
>   1. Required Information: Our process requires users to give their first and last name, state, at least one skill or certification, availability, and amount of time that subscribing companies have access to their resume. 
>   2. Optional Information: Our process gives the option to include address, city, zip code, home and work phone numbers, e-mail address, best-time-to-contact, additional skills/certifications, desired position/objective, career summary, education history, Web resume URL, preferred work location, employment type, travel considerations, security clearance, resume blocking options, citizenship information, how-did-you-hear-about-us, and use-of-other-employment-Web-sites information. 
> 

> * **Prizes and Promotions**  
>  Our online salary survey requires visitors to give us their e-mail addresses. This information is used to contact prize winners, to guard against multiple entries, and to update users with new features/product information.
> *  **Feedback**  
>  ComputerJobs.com encourages feedback from IT professionals. The feedback enables us to continually improve our products and services. All information received through the feedback process becomes the property of ComputerJobs.com and may be used in press materials and advertisements.
> *  **Message Boards**  
>  ComputerJobs.com makes message boards available to its users. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. Users should exercise caution when disclosing personal information to any message board.

       **Information Collected from IT Employers:**

> *  **Client Registration**  
>  To fully utilize the services offered by ComputerJobs.com, employers must complete our client registration. The client registration process requests the following information: 
> 
>   1. Required Information: Our process requires employers to give their company name, e-mail address, password, contact name, address, city, state, zip code, and phone number. 
>   2. Optional Information: Our client registration process gives employers the option to include job ad display defaults, fax number, company URL, global benefits information, notification-when-job-expires, and choices to post to Excite or Yahoo. 
> 

> * **Financial Transactions**  
>  Credit card transactions are processed through CyberCash, a leading third-party credit card processing company. CyberCash only uses your information to complete the appropriate transactions. ComputerJobs.com stores the first two and last four digits of your credit card to complete the verification and approval process. Your entire credit card number is not stored on any ComputerJobs.com system.
> *  **Feedback**  
>  ComputerJobs.com encourages feedback from all employers. All exchange of information between ComputerJobs.com and our employers is confidential unless written permission to use such information for another purpose is given.

   **INFORMATION USE**

ComputerJobs.com is committed to safeguarding your personal information. We take this responsibility very seriously and are continuously looking for improved methods to ensure privacy and security.

> **Use of Information Collected from IT Professionals**
> 
> COMPUTERJOBS.COM DOES NOT SELL YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO ANYONE. It is important to note that information provided in the resume registration process is completely available to subscribing employers. Our employers sign contracts that legally prohibit them from redistributing ComputerJobs.com information without consent. 
> 
> Internally, ComputerJobs.com uses your personal information for validation purposes only. To predict broad trends about our Web site, we request general or generic input from our users in a clearly identifiable fashion, such as our Salary Survey or the Question of the Day.
> 
> **Use of Information Collected from Employers**
> 
> Information collected from employers is not shared with third parties. Employer information is used for contact and billing purposes only. Because of the nature of the ComputerJobs.com Web site, any information that is included on a job listing must be considered public information. ComputerJobs.com provides an anonymous job posting option to exclude contact or company information from public view. IT professionals can only respond to anonymous job postings through an online form which prevents them from knowing the identity of the anonymous job poster.

   **UPDATING OR REMOVING INFORMATION**

ComputerJobs.com gives IT professionals the ability to deactivate their resume by clicking the "Remove your Resume" link on the "My Career" page of My ComputerJobs. This will take the resume out of circulation, but we will hold the candidate's information for the next time they wish to utilize our services. Candidates can log in to activate their account any time they need their resume to be available to employers.

If you have any questions or would like us to remove your resume, email [ usability@ComputerJobs.com](mailto:usability@computerjobs.com) and we will be happy to assist you.

   **LINKS**

Our site contains links to other sites. ComputerJobs.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

   **SECURITY MEASURES**

ComputerJobs.com utilizes industry-standard protocols and procedures to minimize the risk of loss, misuse, or corruption of information. We provide password/login security to protect against unauthorized access. All financial transactions are conducted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology, which encrypts all information that is sent to us. Our security certificate is verified and held by Verisign, using the strongest commercially available encryption on the Internet. Communication between ComputerJobs.com and CyberCash is also conducted via SSL technology.

ComputerJobs.com uses cookies to make your login process easier and more secure. A cookie is a piece of information stored in a small file on your computer. Cookies from ComputerJobs.com do not store any personal information. Our use of cookies is to provide seamless log-in access to all of the different areas of personalization on our site. One use of cookies is to direct your account to log-in automatically and go immediately to the site area you choose to view upon startup. The cookie also contains information that allows us to greet you by name when you enter the personalized area. You may choose to disable cookies and still be able to navigate the site. If cookies are not set on your machine, you will be required to log-in every time you access personalization. The process used to remove cookies from your computer depends on your Web browser.

   **CONTACTING COMPUTERJOBS.COM**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your interactions with this Web site, please contact us at [privacy@ComputerJobs.com ](mailto:privacy@computerjobs.com)or you can reach us at:

3200 Windy Hill Rd.  
Suite 700 West  
Atlanta, GA 30339  
Phone: 770-850-0075  
Fax: 770-850-1128

BY USING OUR SITE, YOU AGREE TO THE TERMS OF OUR PRIVACY STATEMENT. COMPUTERJOBS.COM RESERVES THE RIGHT TO MODIFY OUR STATEMENT AT ANY TIME. Please continue to check this page for changes.   
  
---
